# **Joachim Tan**

#### **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

## **SUMMARY**

I am currently a Penultimate Computer Science Major at the University Of Exeter. My interests are in Full Stack Development and Quantitative Trading.

I have always been interested in the inner workings of websites and applications. I wrote my first few programs in **Python** guided by a book that my parents had bought. The time spent working on them brought me much joy.

I had my first formal coding class when I enrolled in Singapore Polytechnic. I had so much fun doing school projects that I took on my own side projects, making telegram bots and coding a system in C++ that would record my online shop sales. The experience made me fall in love with the process of building products that improve our lives.

During my National Service, I continued pursuing my interest by taking online courses on **SEO**, **Django**, **Figma & React**. These skills helped me build my own website and host my expense tracker telegram bot using **Heroku**.

# **CONTACT**



Hello@JoachimStanislaus.com



loachimStanislaus.com



JoachimStanislaus



<u>JoachimStanislaus</u>



#### RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

## **Data Analyst Intern**

SG Enable May 2022 - Present

- Streamlining Data collection and visualization, improving productivity and reducing visualization time by 50%.
- Manipulating Data to gain further insights, predict trends & sudden spikes in assistance requests to better prepare infrastructure to meet sudden demand.

#### Instructor

Little Coder Jan 2022 - Present

- Languages: Python, Java, Lua, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS
- Software: Scratch, Visual Studio
- Teach and conduct coding, STEM and technology related classes and programs.

# **Engineering Intern**

Royal Dutch Shell Mar 2019 - Aug 2019

2022-2024

- Communicated with the Reliability Department stakeholders on their needs.
- Proposed and developed a solution using VBA that reduced time taken to analyze data by 50%.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Bsc Computer Science**

University Of Exeter 2022-2024

- Entry Into 2nd Year.

# **Diploma in Computer Engineering**

Singapore Polytechnic

- Vice Captain & Treasurer of the Waterpolo Team

## **PROJECTS**

# Climate Hack Hackathon 2022

Team Leader, Technical Lead

# **SKILLS**

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, C++, Java, VBA, Lua, React.js

Tools: Figma, DJango, Git, Bulma, Bootstrap, Bulma